In fact, we operate in a world of prejudice.
事实上，我们生活在一个充满偏见的世界里。
And there, we're going to learn little by little, because we're going to open our eyes wider,
我们将一点一点地学习，因为我们将开阔视野，
it's about living with our eyes a little more open.
用更开阔的眼光生活。
Learning to identify our own patterns.
学会识别我们自己的模式。
And I'm going to suggest that you observe a pattern.
我将建议你观察一个模式。
And if you manage to observe it,
如果你能观察到它，
you can...
你可以...
Most of the time, we use others as
大多数时候，我们把别人当作
our own rags to clean our own windows.
我们自己的抹布来擦拭我们自己的窗户。
Have you ever noticed that in your patterns, you
你有没有注意到，在你的模式中，
have to see this,
你必须看到，
that we project our patterns of satisfaction
我们把我们的满足模式投射到
outside of ourselves?
我们自己之外？
on a subject or an object.
在一个主题或一个对象上。
And then, in fact, one day, we are disappointed.
然后，有一天，我们失望了。
It no longer satisfies me.
他不再让我满意了。
What's important is that at some point,
重要的是，在某个时刻，
we resent the other.
我们怨恨对方。
We'll understand.
我们会明白的。
Suddenly, I resent the other.
突然间，我怨恨对方。
And some go even further.
有些人甚至走得更远。
When we've projected too much outside of ourselves,
当我们投射得太多，投射到我们自己之外时，
we even resent the world.
我们甚至怨恨世界。
So it's about observing.
所以这是观察。
identify our own patterns.
识别我们自己的模式。
One way to achieve this,
实现这一目标的方法之一，
is to meditate.
就是冥想。
If you want to discover your mind,
如果你想发现你的思想，
You do an exercise, you'll see
你做一个练习，你会看到
that after 7 seconds,
7秒钟后，
there will be
会有
thoughts that will arise.
思想涌现。
And suddenly, you are caught
突然间，你被一个想法
by a thought.
催眠了。
And meditation,
而冥想，
it consists of observing that and coming back.
就是观察它并回归。
And the act of learning to observe something neutral
学习观察中立的事物，
teaches you little by little to discover your own patterns which are not neutral.
会让你一点一点地发现你自己的非中立模式。
So there's work and a study of yourself, if you will.
所以，如果你愿意，这是一个自我工作和自我研究。
What do you feel when you see?
当你看到时，你有什么感觉？
It's immediate, it's passive.
它是即时的，它是被动的。
You open your eyes and suddenly the world is there.
你睁开眼睛，突然间世界就在那里。
And often we think that seeing is believing.
我们常常认为眼见为实。
I believe because I saw.
我因为看见了才相信。
So we think that vision is truth.
所以我们认为视觉就是真相。
Learning to understand.
学会理解。
What we see is not in fact a universal truth.
我们所看到的实际上并非普遍真理。
It is not a so-called objective reality.
它不是所谓的客观现实。
When you work, we have prejudices.
当你工作时，我们会有偏见。
And that's what needs to be understood.
这就是需要理解的。
Because nature doesn't know how to take prejudices into account.
因为大自然不会考虑偏见。
The therapeutic process doesn't take that into account, in fact.
治疗过程实际上并没有考虑到这一点。
These are brakes, false fulcrums.
它们是障碍，是假的，是支点。
We create a virtual reality, if you will, and we think it's unique.
如果你愿意，我们创造了一个虚拟现实，我们认为它是独一无二的。
You should know that your visual cortex uses 30% of the mind.
你必须知道你的视觉皮层使用了30%的思维。
your brain, 30%, compared to touch
你的大脑，30%，相比于触觉
which is 8% and hearing which is only 2-3%.
是8%，听觉只有2-3%。
Every second, your eyes are capable of sending about
每秒钟，你的眼睛能够发送大约
2 billion pieces of information
20亿条信息
to your visual cortex, 2 billion.
到你的视觉皮层，20亿。
The rest of your body can only send about a billion.
你身体的其他部分大约只能发送10亿。
that means that sight will represent
这意味着视觉将占据
one third
三分之一
of your brain volume
你的脑容量
and yet it will use
但它会使用
two thirds of your resources
你三分之二的资源
it's not surprising after all
这最终并不令人惊讶
that it's an illusion if it's so important
如果这很重要，那它就是一种幻觉
if I tell you the Papez circuit
如果我告诉你帕佩兹回路
does that mean anything to you
这会让你想起什么吗
all the colliculi and all the amygdaloid
所有丘脑和所有杏仁核
nuclei etc. that will integrate
等等，它们会整合
everything you see
你所看到的一切
influences your emotions.
影响你的情绪。
And your emotions can change what you see.
你的情绪可以改变你所看到的一切。
So that means that sight will become a mental composition.
所以这意味着视觉将成为一种心理构成。
We create our own reality.
我们创造自己的现实。
And what's more, we believe it.
而且，我们还相信它。
So that means it's just one way of forming a reality.
所以这意味着这只是一种形成现实的方式。
For example, fear, have you ever noticed
例如，恐惧，你有没有注意到
how it can distort reality.
它会如何扭曲现实。
I had a child.
我有一个孩子。
like that who came, he was traumatized. They had seen a movie.
就这样来了，他受到了创伤。他们看了一部电影。
It's that he associated being
他把害怕
scared and being in danger. And in fact, the only thing I
和处于危险之中联系起来了。实际上，我唯一做的
did was dissociate. I said,
就是分离。我说，
you were scared, you were afraid, you were scared. But
你害怕了，你感到恐惧了，你害怕了。但是
I said, but you're not in danger.
我说，你并没有处于危险之中。
I saw it suddenly.
我突然看到了。
His reality readjusted, you see.
他的现实，它重新调整了，你明白吗？
And so once you dissociate things again, they fade away, you see.
所以一旦你重新说出这些，事情就会消失，你明白吗？
Because nothing has its own existence.
因为没有什么东西是独立存在的。
Do you understand that?
你明白吗？
Nothing exists by itself.
没有什么东西是独立存在的。
When we understand that, we have a changing view.
当我们明白这一点时，我们的看法就会改变。
Because that means we can understand that even the ego does not exist by itself.
因为这意味着我们可以理解，即使是自我也不是独立存在的。
It becomes a...
它变成了一个……
aggregate, it shows that everything is interdependent and impermanent.
聚合体，这表明一切都是相互依存和无常的。
And impermanence is what
而无常，正是
gives energy, because it gives movement. So it gives your
赋予能量的东西，因为它赋予了运动。所以它赋予了你的
vital energy in fact. It's
生命能量。这是
the chi, since it's a change
气，因为它一直在
all the time. So in fact, if we want to work on that, we must
变化。所以实际上，如果我们想研究这个，我们必须
impermanence. So to open our vision, we must
无常。那么为了拓宽我们的视野，我们
be truly attentive to every moment,
必须真正关注每一个时刻，
to every thought, to every detail. That means we must learn to see beyond
每一个想法，每一个细节。这意味着我们必须学会超越
our
我们的
projections, beyond our fears. That's where we must little by little learn to
投射，超越我们的恐惧。这就是我们必须一点一点地学会
free ourselves from our
摆脱我们的
false interpretations. It's not easy.
错误解读。这并不容易。
Because sometimes, we even want to remain fixed in our ideology.
因为有时候，我们甚至想固守我们的意识形态。
So, it's not complicated.
所以，这并不复杂。
As soon as you think you're in reality, you're wrong.
一旦你认为你处于现实之中，你就错了。
What I propose to you is to increasingly exploit your inner strength.
我建议你们越来越多地利用你们的内在力量。
Exploit, readjust your ideas about luck and success.
利用、调整你们对运气和成功的看法。
Have the right intention.
怀有良好的意图。
This morning, I expressed something to you. We're going to work with your
今天早上，我向你们表达了一些事情。我们将利用你们的
center of gravity,
重心，
your whole body, at the service of your hands. The vital energy is
你们的整个身体，为你们的双手服务。生命能量，它
in the belly.
在腹部。
It's one of the important centers. This impermanence supports
这是一个重要的中心。这种无常支持着
this vital energy.
这种生命能量。
So if you could gradually adjust yourself,
所以，如果我们能逐渐地调整自己，
With your own center, it will be much more powerful, surprisingly.
与你自己的中心连接，那将会强大得多，令人惊讶。
And you could feel a little this morning, when I asked you to adjust yourself.
今天早上，当我让你们调整时，你们可能已经感觉到了一点。
I did it, I made you adjust, you just have to adjust.
我做到了，我让你调整了，你只需要调整。
Because we're going to work with three main types of energy, three main types of movement.
因为我们将使用三种主要的能量类型，三种主要的运动类型。
We're going to work with induced movement, we're going to work with permitted movement,
我们将使用诱导运动，我们将使用允许运动，
and we're going to work with present movement.
我们将使用当下运动。
I can induce something.
我可以诱导一些东西。
I must do it consciously.
我必须有意识地去做。
Or I can follow something.
或者我可以跟随一些东西。
Or I can just listen to the present moment.
或者我可以倾听当下。
So it's accepting your strength, accepting your weakness.
所以，这是接受自己的力量，接受自己的弱点。
And also understanding the difference between that.
并理解其中的区别。
And opening your heart to these countless possibilities that are
并向这些无数的可能性敞开心扉，它们就在
there.
那里。
Often...
通常...
When I have people like that who come with quite acute problems,
当我有这样的人，带着相当严重的、
not with small, quite acute, depressive, quite deep problems, things
不是小问题，而是相当严重的、抑郁的、相当深层的问题，诸如此类的
like that,
事情时，
I ask them a question, I say, "When you're healed, what will you be able to do?"
我问他们一个问题，我说，听着，当你康复后，你能做什么？
What will you be able to do again?
你还能做什么？
It's a whole new program that sometimes they hadn't even thought about.
这是一个全新的计划，有时他们甚至没有想到。
It's important, because you create a direction.
这很重要，因为你创造了一个方向。
And that's it, you have to work with health.
就是这样，我们必须与健康合作。
We should not work with illness or against illness, we should work
我们不应该与疾病合作或对抗疾病，我们应该与
with health.
健康合作。
And so sometimes this passage is very narrow, directing our attention towards
因此，有时这个通道非常狭窄，将我们的注意力引向
health.
健康。